Guide to the Stanford University, Program in Ethics in Society, Honors Theses
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in Ethics in Society, honors theses
1992-2008
SC4-3445
Stanford University. Program in Ethics in Society.
1 Linear feet (20 volumes in 2 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in Ethics in Society at Stanford University.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in Ethics in Society at Stanford University.
Access Terms
Ethics--Study and teaching.; Student papers.
Collection Contents
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Bae, Richard, Breaking down trust: managed care's effect on the patient-physician relationship., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Catherine, Autonomy and disease prevention in population-based genetic screening: a case study., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Beerbohm, Eric, Welfare justice: a Rawlsian response to the Personal Responsibility Act of 1996., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Friedland, Michelle, Scheduled people and the environment: an adaption of Rawls's Theory of Justice., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Gandhi, Nandini, Sorting students by ability in elementary schools: a civic approach., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Gordon, Tracy, Toward a "health care ethics": implications of Rawls' "Justice as fairness" and Nozick's modern libertarianism for the design of a just health care system., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Johnstone, Mattie, Freedom and responsibility: the right to reproductive autonomy and China's one-child policy., 2001 (Box 1)
  - Maddow, Rachel, Identifiable lives: AIDS and the response to dehumanization., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Parang, Touraj, Autonomy, Ulysses contracts, and dementia: respecting the autonomy of dementia patients., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Rosenbloom, Seth, The legitimacy of South African judical review for social and economic rights., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Shapiro, Joseph, The ethics and efficacy of banning human kidney sales., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Slattery, Ian, Confronting colorblindness: assessing the morality of "colorblind" racial ideology., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Wood, Anne, The ethics of parental control: an inquiry into homeschooling., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Shane, Michelle, An inconvenient truth: the situation of children with autism in special education., 2007 (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Natausha A., Common schooling in Northern Ireland: a theoretic and pragmatic analysis of multicultural/integrated education., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Young, Angie, Providing a justification for parental leave and designing a policy., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Yusim, Anna, The limits of responsibility and the inadequacy of desert: a philosophical quest for justice in health care., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Stewart, Applying the philosophy of John Stuart Mill to the issue of drug prohibition., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Yip, Jennifer, Servility and self-respect reconsidered: a case study of Filipina domestic helpers in Hong Kong., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Hunter Osprey, Elimination or preservation: a practical model for intuitive arguments undrelying the philosophy of race., 2008 (Box 2)